JACOB CALDWELL

• DETAILS •

Memphis, TN 7314600648 jscaldwell95@gmail.com

• LINKS •

jacobcaldwell.com

LinkedIn

Github

• SKILLS •

Python

Java

Node.js

React

SQL

JavaScript

Typescript

Google Cloud Platform

Angular

GraphQL

Git

PROFILE

Goal-oriented engineer with extensive experience in developing electrical, mechanical and software systems. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including React, Typescript, Google Cloud Platform, Python and Java. Committed to working as a collaborative and positive team member, striving to utilize my knowledge and expertise for the greatest results.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

R&D Engineer at ABB, Memphis, TN

January 2019 — Present

- Lead multiple high priority projects though the product development cycle designing a wide range of products currently used in the electrical industry.
- Worked to develop new product lines and extend existing lines valued at more than \$60 million.
- Designed and developed novel, innovative products that decreased costs for customers and offered a solution greater than existing ones.
- Helped spearhead the use of low volume digital manufacturing solutions to accelerate the product development cycle and decrease the time to market.
- Created multiple software tools and automation programs to increase efficiency and decrease the amount of time spent on mundane tasks.

Software Development/Engineering Systems Intern at Thomas & Betts, Memphis, TN June 2016 — December 2018

- Designed, developed and deployed multiple full stack web apps to submit, track, and archive rapid prototyping requests and FEA/simulation requests
- Designed software focused on increase productivity and automating mundane tasks.
- Standardized the collection and distribution of all engineering documentation with a custom SharePoint site.

Electrical Engineering Researcher at Christian Brothers University, Memphis, TN May 2017 — January 2018

- Invented a new algorithm to improve the detection of edges in noise corrupted images.
- Publish: "On Image Enhancement for Edge Detection" IESTOC 2017, Vol. 15 No. 2

EDUCATION

Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, Christian Brothers University, Memphis August 2014 - December 2018

- · Minor: Mathematics
- Senior Project: Celestial Object Tracking Camera System.
- Undergraduate research focused on image enhancement and edge detection

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

IEEE

August 2015 — Present

• IEEE National Paper Competition - 4th Place Finalist